## **AARON VONTELL**

860-805-0050 vontell@mit.edu github.com/vontell

229 Vassar Street Cambridge, MA 02139

#### **Profile**

I am a freshman at Massachusetts Institute of Technology, pursuing a degree in Electrical Engineering and Computer Science. I have four years of computer programming experience, mainly in Java and Android. I also completed a summer internship at Cigna on an Android Application Developer team. I am currently working with two startups.

# **Experience**

Android Application Developer, Cigna; Bloomfield, CT — Summer 2014 Duties included developing proof-of-concept software and Android applications using the Java programming language, in conjunction with external libraries and devices. Multiple projects were completed in accordance to a schedule, and collaboration and teamwork were used throughout each project.

Lead Software Developer, Parcio; Boston, MA — 2014 - Present Duties include developing an Android and iOS application with the startup Parcio. The application includes work with Google APIs, MapQuest Open APIs, Android SDK, iOS development, and a custom REST API. Also requires multiple meetings with city officials and the Department of Transportation. See more at parcio.com

Chief Technology Officer, UpStudent; Cambridge, MA — 2014 - Present Duties include guiding and tutoring students through the college application process, through a detailed lesson plan, simulated interviews, and post-acceptance meetings. Also includes all development of our company's website using Bootstrap and hosting through Github. See more at myupstudent.com

Admissions Employee, Lake Compounce; Bristol, CT — 2013-2014 Duties at this amusement park included working a register efficiently, conversing with guests to help them with any issues, and working as a team to sustain the park's image. My main assignments were working the cash registers and working in Guest Relations to help guests with anything from lost tickets to lost children.

## Education

Attended University High School of Science and Engineering, 2010 - 2014

40+ college credits from University of Hartford during high school, 2011 - 2014

Currently enrolled in Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 2014 - present

Pursuing Electrical Engineering and Computer Science Major, Minor in Management

#### Skills

Java Programming (3+ years)

Android Programming (Including multiple APIs) (1 year)

Project Management (From a leadership role on a FIRST Robotics team for 6 years)

Photoshop CS6

Minimal Experience in HTML, CSS, Objective-C, and Python

Autodesk Inventor Professional

## **Volunteer Work**

Treasurer of National Honor Society (2013)

Volunteer at Imagine Nation Museum (2010-2012)

Cavalier Club (Community/Fundraising Club) (2013-2014)